(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
エネルギー連結...ok
Energy connection...ok
インテリジェンスチェック...ok
Intelligence check...ok
世界座標再構築...ok
World coordinate reconstruction...ok
システム起動...
System startup...
NAKIRI AYAME
いくよ！
Here we go!
Q&A リサイタル!
Q&A Recital!
今日もこの胸は 張り詰めたまま
Today, too, my heart remains tense
放課後に包まれて 君を見てるレディレディ
Wrapped in the after-school glow, I'm watching you, lady lady
ずっと足並みは 揃わないまま
Our steps remain out of sync
続くから内緒だよ 少しずつレレレディレディ
It'll continue, so it's a secret, bit by bit, le-le-lady lady
知りすぎて知らないから
Because I know too much, yet I don't know anything
Question Answer
聞こえないふりが上手になって
I've gotten better at pretending not to hear
Question Answer
ねえ深呼吸一つしたら目を開けて
Hey, take a deep breath, and then open your eyes
自問自答やめて何気なくおはようって言っちゃってる
I stop second-guessing myself and casually say good morning
飽きるくらい全部君が欲しいよ
I want everything about you, until I'm tired of it
ハートは涙でいっぱい
My heart is full of tears
恋のいろはとかまだわかってないんだ
I still don't understand the basics of love
何度も繰り返すけど
I keep repeating it, but...
寸前でまた次回へ
At the very last moment, it's 'until next time' again
甘い乙女心はあいにく取り扱ってないのです
Unfortunately, a sweet maiden's heart is not something I handle
ねえ、これがI love you?
Hey, is this 'I love you'?
やっと手に入れたはずのパノラマ
The panorama I was finally supposed to have in hand
二歩進み 二歩下がる
Two steps forward, two steps back
なんで？ だけど lady ready go!
Why? But lady ready go!
ゴールできなくちゃ 止まれないから
I can't stop until I reach the goal
分からないままでもね いいよ だから lady ready
It's okay even if I don't understand, so lady ready
昨日の答えなんてさ プレッシャー A answer
Yesterday's answer is like pressure, A answer
今日の答えの前では プレッシャー ほらね A answer
In front of today's answer, see, pressure A answer
もう隠せそうもないくらい 好きだから
Because I love you so much I can't hide it anymore
知らないことは いつか知れたらいいかなって言っちゃおうかな
Should I say it's fine if I learn what I don't know someday?
とりとめないシーンでも 大事だからね アンダーラインは引いて
Even in rambling scenes, they're important, so underline them
恋の試験科目に 加えておいてよ
Add them to the subjects of the love exam
時に君の心に 何百マイルのディスタンス
Sometimes, hundreds of miles of distance in your heart
なんてね 気にしすぎかな だけどそれが本心なのです
Just kidding, maybe I'm worrying too much, but that's how I truly feel
こんな、あんな時はどうしたらいいの？
What should I do in times like this or that?
慣れたメロディを 口ずさむように
Like humming a familiar melody
君の中の私は どこにいるの？
Where am I inside of you?
ぐるぐる回って 四六時中、リサイタル！
Spinning round and round, a recital 24/7!
Someday I really really send it, precious for you!
Someday I really really send it...
いつかその日がきたら 大切な声を聞いて
If that day ever comes, listen to the precious voice
恋に予約録画は ありえないから
Because there's no scheduled recording for love
逃さまいで
Don't let it get away
飽きるくらい全部 君が好きだよ ハートは笑顔でいっぱい
I love everything about you to the point of getting tired of it, my heart is full of smiles
恋のいろはも 少し分かりたいんだ
I want to understand the basics of love a little too
何度も繰り返すけど 続きでまた次回へ
I repeat it many times, but to be continued next time
Sweetな乙女心は 依然取り扱ってないのです
Sweet girlish hearts are still not being handled
ねえ、これが I love you?
Hey, is this I love you?
Someday I really really send it, precious for you!
いっせーのーで君とだけ
On the count of one, two, with only you
もう少し眠りたいけど もったいないよ 今日は Sunday
I want to sleep a bit more, but it's a waste, today is Sunday
楽しいこと やりたいこと Wake up 始めようよ
Fun things, things I want to do, wake up let's get started
めくるめく季節君と 次のステージへ
The dazzling seasons with you, to the next stage
声を合わせ 扉開けて 駆け出せ迷わずに
Unite our voices, open the door, and run out without hesitation
転んでもかっこ悪くてもイイじゃない
It's okay even if I fall or look uncool
Stand up イメージもっと重ねて行くその先で
Stand up, as we layer our images more and more, beyond that...
いっせーのーで君とだけ ハイタッチ手叩いて 奏でるメロディを
On the count of one, two, with only you, high-fiving, the melody we play
合図に走り出せ Go! 君となら怖くないよ
At the signal, start running, Go! With you, I'm not afraid
ハイタッチ手と手叩いて 重ねるそのメモリは 明日へのエネルギー
High-fiving, hand to hand, the memories we stack are energy for tomorrow
Yeah! さあ行こうよ もっと先へ 君とならハッピーな未来
Yeah! Let's go, further ahead, with you, it's a happy future
あの日見た夢の続き 追いつくその日まで
Until the day I catch up to the continuation of the dream I saw that day
涙なんて 振り切るくらい もっとスピードアップ!!
Speed up more, so much that I shake off my tears!!
どんな未来になっても
No matter what the future holds
後悔しないよ
I won't regret it
自分自身選んだ道
The path I chose for myself
踏み出せ　迷わずに
Step forward without hesitation
落ち込んで進めなくなった時は
When you're depressed and can't move forward
Wake Up！
Wake Up!
思い返す夢見た頃の記憶を
Recall the memories of when you dreamed
手と手叩いて奏でる　煌めく夢は君とだけ
Clapping hands and playing together, a sparkling dream is only with you
ハイタッチの度に　繋がっていく心
Every time we high-five, our hearts connect
ひとりじゃないことをそう　気づかせてくれたよね
You made me realize that I'm not alone
ハイタッチ手と手叩いて　奏でるそのメロディーが
High-five, clapping hands, that melody we play
世界に届くまで　この夢は続いてく
This dream will continue until it reaches the world
君とならハッピーラッキー！
With you, I'm happy-lucky!
挫けて歩けない日は　おんぶしてあげる君を
On days when you're discouraged and can't walk, I'll give you a piggyback ride
ほら見てそっちの方が　強く地面踏み込める
Look, you can step on the ground more firmly that way
巡り巡る日々を辿り　夢見たステージへ
Tracing the days that come and go, to the stage I dreamed of
届くその日を見つめて
Looking toward the day it reaches
起こそう君とだけ
Let's make it happen, only with you
手と手を鳴らすたび　小さなビッグバン
Every time we clap hands, a small Big Bang
無限のその力を　受けて進め！！
Receive that infinite power and move forward!!
ハイタッチ手と手叩いて　奏でるメロディーを
High-five, clapping hands, the melody we play
合図に走り出せ　君となら怖くない
Start running at the signal, with you I'm not afraid
ハイタッチ手と手叩いて　重ねるそのメモリーは
High-five, clapping hands, the memories we accumulate
明日へのエネルギー　さあ行こうよ　もっと先へ
Energy for tomorrow, let's go even further
君とならハッピーラッキー！
With you, I'm happy-lucky!
おー！みんな見てますかー！よーだぞー！
Oh! Is everyone watching? Yo-dazo!
ということで、ホロライブ2期生の百鬼あやめです！イエーイ！見てるー？
So, I'm Nakiri Ayame from Hololive's 2nd Generation! Yay! Are you watching?
ということでですね、あーちょっと歌って踊って、あのヘトヘトなんですけど
Anyway, ah, I'm a bit exhausted from singing and dancing...
1曲目はQ&Aリサイタルで、2曲目はハイタッチメモリーをちょっと踊らせていただきましたー！
For the first song I performed "Q&A Recital!", and for the second song I danced to "Hi-Touch Memory"!
ということで今日はね、あの本来は9月13日だったんですけど
So today, well, it was originally supposed to be on September 13th...
今日10月2日にね、3Dでデビューしてからの3周年記念ライブをしていきたいと思いまーす！
but today, October 2nd, I'm going to hold my 3rd anniversary 3D live!
ということで今日は、ゲストをたくさん呼んでいるので
Since I've invited many guests today...
今日の放送の最後には嬉しいお知らせも、あったりなかったりするので、最後まで見ててくださーい！
there might be some happy news at the end of today's stream, so please watch until the end!
じゃあもうジャンジャンね、ちょっとゲストと一緒に歌って踊っていっちゃおうかなーと思いまーすよ！
Now, I'm going to sing and dance with the guests one after another!
今度は誰が来るのか、みんなちょっと予想しておいて待っててね。
Everyone, please try to guess who's coming next while you wait.
じゃあ早速1人目を呼んでいっちゃおうかなと思いまーすよ。
Well then, I'll call out the first person right away.
ということで、1人目はー
And so, the first person is...
おかゆー！
Okayu!
うわー！来てくれてありがとうー！
Whoa! Thank you for coming!
きたよーあやめー！
I'm here, Ayame!
ピタピタピタ…ハイタッチ！
Pita-pita-pita... High five!
ということで今日は、おかゆが来てくれましたー！
So today, Okayu has joined us!
あやめちゃん3周年おめでとう！
Ayame-chan, happy 3rd anniversary!
ありがとうー！イエーイイエーイ！
Thank you! Yay yay!
ということでね、なんだかんだ、おかゆたちってさー
So, you know, somehow Okayu and I...
ご飯行ったりとかさ、遊んだりして、ゲームやったりね。
go out to eat, hang out, and play games together.
そうゲームしてるんですけど、あんまり意外に3Dで歌って踊ることなくて
Right, we play games, but surprisingly we don't often sing and dance together in 3D.
確かに。
That's true.
今日が初めてらしい。踊ることも、あんまりないもんね。
Apparently today is the first time. We don't usually dance together either.
じゃあ、イエーイ！スクショとか撮っておいてください。イエーイ！お願いします。
So, yay! Please take some screenshots. Yay! Thank you.
ということで今日は、歌って踊るわけなんですけど。
So today, we're going to sing and dance.
なんかちょっとおかゆと何歌って踊ろうかなーって考えた時に
When I was thinking about what Okayu and I should sing and dance to...
おかゆがね「この曲あやめちゃんと一緒に歌って踊りたいんだけど」って
Okayu said, "I want to sing and dance to this song with Ayame-chan."
そう、歌いたい曲があってね。それを今日一緒に歌いたいと思います。
Yes, there's a song I wanted to sing. We'll sing it together today.
やったー！ということでね、早速歌っていっちゃいますか？
Yay! So, shall we start singing right away?
いっちゃいますか？
Shall we?
じゃあ行きますよー！よし、レッツゴー！
Then here we go! Alright, let's go!
言って。
作詞作曲：n-buna
Say it.
Lyrics and Composition: n-buna
あのね、私実は気付いてるの
You know, I actually noticed
ほら、君がいったこと
Look, what you said
あまり考えたいと思えなくて
I didn't really want to think about it
忘れてたんだけど
I had forgotten, but
盲目的に 盲導的に 妄想的に生きて
Living blindly, being led blindly, living in delusions
衝撃的な 焦燥的な 消極的なままじゃダメだったんだ
Being shocking, impatient, and passive just wasn't enough
きっと、人生最後の日を前に思うのだろう
I'll surely think about it before the last day of my life
全部、全部言い足りなくて悔しいけど
It's frustrating that I can't say it all, but
ああ、いつか人生最後の日、君がいないことを
Ah, that one day on the last day of my life, you won't be there
もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、ちゃんと言って
Say it more, more, more, more, clearly
あのね
You know
空が青いのってどうやって伝えればいいんだろうね
How should I convey that the sky is blue?
夜の
The night's
雲が高いのってどうすれば君もわかるんだろう
How can I make you understand that the clouds are high?
言って
Say it
あのね
You know
私実はわかってるの
I actually know
もう君がいったこと
What you already said
あのね
You know
わからずやって言うんだろうね
I guess you'd call it being stubborn
忘れたいんだけど
I want to forget, but
もっとちゃんと言ってよ
Say it more clearly
忘れないようメモにしてよ
Make a memo so I don't forget
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's meet at the station platform tomorrow at 10
牡丹は散っても花だ
A peony is still a flower even when it falls
夏が去っても追憶は切な
Even when summer is gone, the memory is painful
口に出して
Speak it out
声に出して
Voice it out
君が言って
You say it
そして人生最後の日、君が見えるのなら
And if I can see you on the last day of my life
きっと、人生最後の日も愛を歌うのだろう
Surely, I will sing of love even on the last day of my life
全部、全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
Because I'll say that nothing, nothing was in vain
ああ、いつか人生最後の日、君がいないことが
Ah, that one day on the last day of my life, your absence
まだ信じられないけど
I still can't believe it, but
もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと
More, more, more, more, more, more, more
君がもっと、もっと、もっと、もっと、もっと
You, more, more, more, more, more
ちゃんと言って
Say it clearly
あー、歌ったねー。
Ah, we sang it!
歌ったー！
We did!
ありがと、おかゆ、歌ってくれて。めっちゃ楽しかった！
Thanks, Okayu, for singing with me. It was so much fun!
ねー、余もこの歌大好きだったから、おかゆに歌いたいって言ってくれたことがすごい嬉しかったんだよね。
Yeah, I really love this song too, so I was so happy when you said you wanted to sing it.
あ、そう、あやめちゃんはこの曲めっちゃ好きそうだなぁ、もしかして知ってるかなぁと思って。
Ah, right, I thought you'd really like this song, Ayame-chan, and wondered if you knew it.
あ、そう！大好き！知ってる、うん。この曲にしたかったんだよね。
Ah, yeah! I love it! I know it, yeah. I wanted to make it this song.
あ、そうだったの？あ、じゃあ合わせてもらってありがとうございます。
Oh, really? Well, thanks for going along with it.
いやいや、一緒にさ、綺麗系の歌を歌いたかったの。
No, no, I wanted to sing a beautiful-style song together.
あ、そうだよね。綺麗系歌いたいって言ってくれてて。
Ah, right. You said you wanted to sing something beautiful.
そうなの、そうなの。あやめちゃんとさ、絶対いいよーみたいな。
That's right, that's right. Like, it'll definitely be great with Ayame-chan.
いつもの通り持ち上げてくれてね。
As always, you're flattering me.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho.
じゃあ「言って」歌ったことでね、はい。じゃあ僕は行きます！
Well, now that we've sung "Say it", alright. Well, I'm off!
あー！行かないでー！
Ah! Don't go!
ということでね、あの、行ってしまわれましたけれど。また...
And with that, well, she's gone off. Next...
次は、次のゲストもいるのかな？
Next... Is there another guest coming too?
おっ？ あ、あ？
Oh? Ah, ah?
あ、なんかちょっと準備ができたそうなので、
Ah, it seems like they're ready,
2曲目も呼んでいっちゃおうかなと思いますよ～！
So I'm going to call them out for the second song!
ころね～！
Korone!
わあああ！ おめでとおお！
Waaah! Congratulations!
おっ？ あれ？ あれれ？
Oh? Wait? Huh?
わあ！ おめでとおおお！
Waa! Congratulatioooons!
あやめ、こんな、こんなおめでたい時に呼んでくれてありがとうございます！
Ayame, thank you so much for inviting me on such a special occasion!
いいえ、ありがとうございます、来てくれてありがとうございます。
No, thank you, thank you for coming.
あやめ、大好きだー、愛してるよー！
Ayame, I love you, I love you so much!
今日はね、あの、一緒にね、歌って踊りたい曲があったんだって。
Today, you see, I heard there's a song you wanted us to sing and dance to together.
あるんですよ！
There is!
あるんだよ、ちょっと言ってやってくださいよ。
There is. Go ahead and tell them.
えっ、もう歌って踊る曲、言っちゃっていいんですか？
Eh, can I already say which song we're singing and dancing to?
あの、なんか頑張ったこと、言ってあげてくださいよ。
Please tell them about how hard you worked for this.
そうだね、なんかこっそり、一緒にころねとダンスレッスンをね、
That's right. Secretly, I had dance lessons with Korone,
ちょっとこっそりしたんですよ、一緒にね。
We did it secretly together.
頑張りたいなと思って、ダンスちょっと余（あやめ）苦手なんですけど、
I wanted to do my best, even though I'm not very good at dancing,
ちょっとね、ころねとやりたいなと思って、一生懸命練習してきました！
I really wanted to do it with Korone, so I practiced really hard!
なので、今日はお披露目、お披露目したいと思います！ 頑張ってるところを。
So, today I'd like to showcase it! The result of my hard work.
みんなちゃんと見ててくださいね！
Everyone, please watch closely!
見ててよー！ 見ててよー！
Watch us! Watch us!
ということで、じゃあ言っちゃいますか！
So, shall we say it?
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
ダメダメよ★
No way, no way★
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
作詞・作曲:SAM
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
Lyrics/Composition: SAM
右から左へと 言葉が流れる
From right to left, words flow by
退屈そうな顔 画面見つめる君
With a bored face, you stare at the screen
次元の壁越えて いつでも会いに行く
Crossing the dimensional wall, I'll go see you anytime
心の準備を ちゃんとしておいてね
So make sure you're mentally prepared
君のこと誰よりも 分かってる だから私に任せて
I understand you better than anyone else, so leave it to me
怖がらないで二人で 踊りましょ!!!
Don't be afraid, let's dance together!!!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
はじけるリズムに合わせて
To the popping rhythm
嫌なこと何もかも 全部忘れて
Forget all the bad things
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
私はここにいるから
Because I am right here
少しでも視線を そらしちゃダメダメよ★
Don't even look away for a second, no way, no way★
重くて見れない日 荒らしに釣られた日
On days when it's too laggy to watch, or you're baited by trolls
心で呼んでみて すぐに飛んで行くわ
Try calling me in your heart, I'll fly to you immediately
授業では教わらない ことを君に教えてあげるわ
I'll teach you things you don't learn in class
夜の扉を二人で 開きましょう
Let's open the door of the night together
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
溢れる想いはFor You
These overflowing feelings are for you
限りあるこの時を 胸に刻んで
Engrave this limited time in your heart
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
朝日が昇ればサヨナラ
Goodbye when the morning sun rises
寂しそうなそんな目 されてもダメだから
Even if you give me those lonely eyes, it's no good
君のこと誰よりも 分かってる だからすべてをさらして
I understand you better than anyone else, so reveal everything
生まれた意味を二人で 見つけましょう!!
Let's find the meaning of our birth together!!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
高まる鼓動を感じて
Feel the rising heartbeat
さあ覚悟できたら この手をとって...
Now, if you're ready, take this hand...
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
輝く君が好きなの
I love you when you're shining
全力で飛び出そう 用意はいいかしら？
Let's jump out with all our might, are you ready?
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
はじけるリズムに合わせて
To the popping rhythm
嫌なこと何もかも 全部忘れて
Forget all the bad things
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka ★ Night Fever
私はここにいるから
Because I am right here
少しでも視線を そらしちゃダメダメよ★
Don't even look away for a second, no way, no way★
ダメダメよ☆
No, no, no!☆
お疲れ様でしたー！
Great job everyone!
イェーイ！
Yay!
すごかった！
That was amazing!
え、ちょっと何かいい感じに踊れてた？
Wait, did I dance okay?
踊れてた踊れてた！
You danced great!
すごかったよ、ありがとう！
It was amazing, thank you!
みんなも可愛かったよね！
Everyone was so cute too!
OK!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
あやめる本当頑張ってたからね。
Ayame really worked hard for this.
いや何かもうすごい、激しくて...
Yeah, it was so intense...
ダンス初心者にとってもめちゃめちゃ難しかったんですけど...
It was extremely difficult for a beginner dancer like me...
あやめる本当にね、頑張ってたからみんなに今日見せられて良かったね。
Ayame really gave it her all, so I'm glad everyone got to see it today.
一生懸命踊りました！
I danced with all my might!
ありがとう、一緒に踊れて良かった。
Thank you, I'm glad we could dance together.
あ、良かった、ありがとうね。
Ah, I'm so glad, thank you.
え、何かさ初めてでしょ？
Wait, isn't this the first time?
そうだよ！
That's right!
ちょっと1枚くらいさ、写真撮りたくない？
Don't you want to take at least one photo?
お、ちょっといいですか？カメラマンさんいいですか？
Oh, is that okay? Is it okay, Mr. Cameraman?
え、どういうポーズが、どういうのがいいかな？
Wait, what kind of pose would be good?
最後さ、ハートマークちゃんと出来なかった...
At the end, we couldn't make the heart shape properly...
あ、そうだね。ここでちゃんと...
Ah, you're right. Let's do it properly here...
いい感じですか？ハートになってますか？
Does it look okay? Is it a heart?
何か割れてない？
Isn't it broken?
あ、ちょっと変...
Ah, it's a bit weird...
何か割れてるよね。
It looks broken, doesn't it?
分かった！ちょっとさ、プリクラのフレームみたいにしてさ...
I know! Let's make it like a photo booth frame...
あ、3周年をさ、こうやって、どうですか？写したら。
Ah, like this around the "3rd Anniversary". How about this for the photo?
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
イェーイ！3周年だよー！
Yay! It's the 3rd anniversary!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いい写真が撮れたのではないでしょーか。
I think we got a good photo.
見た？見たかな？
Did you see it? I wonder if they saw it.
ちゃんと保存しておけよー。
Make sure you save it!
カメラマンさんOKですか？OK？OK！
Mr. Cameraman, are you OK? OK? OK!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ということでね、あやめるはね...
So, Ayame still has...
まだまだこれからありますよ、またねダンスと歌が待ってるので。
...more coming up, with more dancing and singing ahead.
本当に楽しみだね、みんな。
I'm really looking forward to it, everyone.
ちょっとみんな楽しみに！
Everyone, please look forward to it!
じゃ、コロネそこで見てるから。
Well, Korone will be watching from over there.
あ、いいの？じゃ、ちょっと観客席の方に...
Ah, really? Then I'll head to the audience seats...
じゃあね！ありがとうね、ありがとう！
See ya! Thank you so much!
頑張れー！
Good luck!
頑張るね！
I'll do my best!
ということで、コロネが一緒に踊ってくれて、いやもうちょっと...
So, Korone danced with me, and I'm a bit...
ゼーゼーハーハーしておりますけれども。
...out of breath right now.
まだまだ曲はありますので、一生懸命頑張って歌いますよ。
But there are still more songs, so I'll do my best to sing them.
ゼーゼーしないようにね. ということで次の曲は...
I'll try not to gasp for air. So, the next song is...
ちょっとエモい感じかなと思いますので、お楽しみに！
...one that's a bit emotional, I think, so please look forward to it!
じゃあね！
See ya!
ebb and flow
降り積もる粉雪が舞う
The fallen powder snow dances
諦めかけた夢がまた
The dream I was about to give up on once again
波打つ　あの日のままで
Is surging, just like that day
変わらない笑顔見つめた
I gazed at your unchanging smile
染まる頬に触れた風が
The wind that touched my blushing cheeks
空高く抜けた
Passed through high up into the sky
いつも見ていた　近いようで遠くて
I was always watching, seemingly close yet so far
いつだって届かない
It never reaches
どうして？　問いかけた声も
Why? Even the voice that questioned
揺れる
Is shaking
ゆらゆら　水面に浮かんだ月は何を
Swaying, what does the moon floating on the water's surface
語らないただの傍観者
Not say, just a mere bystander?
同じ目　握る手が痛い
The same eyes, the hand I grip is hurting
悪戯な風が吹く朝
The morning when a mischievous wind blows
木の葉じゃれ合う声に合わせて
Matching the sound of leaves playing together
駆け出す君を
As you start to run
ただ夢中で追いかけてた
I was just chasing after you frantically
その横顔が見てるのは
What that profile of yours is looking at
遥か遠くここじゃなくて
Is far, far away, and not here
ebb and flow
海が満ち また引いてゆく夕凪
The tide rises and falls again in the evening calm
心の岸に打ち寄せられた
Washed onto the shore of my heart
決意は明日の光に
was a resolution for tomorrow's light
信じて
Believe
ねぇ 問いかけた声が
Hey, the voice I called out with
響く
echoes
ハラハラと 舞い散る夜空
Fluttering down through the night sky
駆けて行けば
if I run
あの丘に 日差しさす頃に
By the time the sun shines on that hill
見つけた願いは宝石
the wish I found is a jewel
輝き出す
that begins to shine
アリシア
作詞・作曲 毛蟹
Alicia
Lyrics & Composition: Kegani
誰かの描いた シナリオじゃなくて
It's not a scenario drawn by someone else
私たちの道 見つけた
but the path we've found together
誰だって探してる 自分だけのストーリー
Everyone is looking for their own story
噂話 頼りに 飛び回る蝶みたい
Like a butterfly fluttering around, relying on rumors
夜の路地裏 静かな声
A back alley at night, a quiet voice
駅の雑踏 心の隙間
The station's hustle, a gap in the heart
何もかもを 横目に置いていく
Leaving everything behind as I pass by
ただ一つの 本物手に入れるために
To get my hands on the one true thing
流れてく前に 消えていく前に
Before it flows away, before it disappears
知らない未来が あるのなら
If there's a future I don't know...
誰かの描いた シナリオじゃなくて
Not a scenario drawn by someone else
手を繋いだままで 進んでる
We're moving forward with our hands held tight
私たちの道 見つけた
We've found our path
誰だって迷ってる 自分だけのラビリンス
Everyone is lost in their own labyrinth
地図のない 狭い暗い世界 扉はどこに
In a narrow, dark world with no map, where is the door?
読みかけの 破れた日記
A half-read, torn diary
書きかけの 心の在り処
The unfinished whereabouts of the heart
どれも全部 残していくけど
I'll leave it all behind, but...
ただ一つの 希望は抱えていくから
I'll keep holding onto just one hope
遥か遠い先に たどり着く先に
In the far distance, at the destination I reach
知らない未来が あるのなら
If there's a future I don't know...
誰かの望んだ シナリオじゃなくて
Not a scenario desired by someone else
目を凝らして 初めて見える
For the first time, I can see by looking closely
私たちの道 見つけた
We've found our path
アリシア
Alicia
置いていく風景も
The scenery being left behind
残した想いも
And the feelings left behind
心の隙間もありかも
Maybe even the gaps in my heart are okay
全部が全部いつかきらめいて
One day, everything will sparkle
自分の後ろにできる足音
The sound of footsteps behind me
流れていく歳月でも
Even as the years flow by
消えていく歳月でも
Even as the years fade away
知りたい未来があるのなら
If there's a future you want to know
誰かの描いたシナリオじゃなくて
It's not a scenario drawn by someone else
手を繋いだままで進める
We can move forward while holding hands
私たちの道見つけて
Find our own path
はい！ということで、
Yes! So,
さっきはね、ちょっと教会のほうで
Earlier, at the church,
一人でエモい曲をちょっと歌わせていただいたんですけれども
I sang an emotional song alone,
まだまだ続きますよ、こっから。
but it continues from here.
ちょっとね、ゲストもまだまだちょっと控えているのでね
The guest is still waiting,
ちょっと早速なんですけど
so without further ado,
お！あれ？
Oh! Huh?
ゲスト3人目ですね！
It's the third guest!
3人目のゲスト、ちょっと呼んで、早速歌っていきたいと思いますよ。
I'll call the third guest and start singing right away.
じゃあ、3人目は一体誰が来るんでしょうか！
Now, who could the third guest be!
うわぁぁぁぁぁ！
Waaaaah!
あ、ノエルちゃんだ！
Ah, it's Noel-chan!
今か今かとずっと待ってました。団長です！
I've been waiting for this moment. It's Danchou!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ありがとう、来てくれて。
Thank you for coming.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
とんでもない。あやめ先輩の3周年だったら
Not at all. For Ayame-senpai's 3rd anniversary,
もう喜んで駆けつけます。どこにいても。
I'd happily rush here, no matter where I am.
え、いいんですか？
Oh, is that so?
当たり前じゃないですか！
Of course!
でもなんかちょっと最近、
But lately,
よく一緒に3Dをしてるんじゃないですか？
haven't we been doing 3D together a lot?
嬉しいな。
I'm so happy.
でも今日も、お呼びいただきありがとうございます。
But thank you for inviting me today too.
今日もね、ちょっと可愛い曲を
Today, with a cute song,
ノエルちゃんと一緒に歌って踊っちゃおうかなと思います。
I'm thinking of singing and dancing with Noel-chan.
やったー！
Yay!
やりましょう！
Let's do it!
じゃあ早速いきますか。
Then shall we get started?
お、いきますか。
Oh, shall we?
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
ドキッ！こういうのが恋なの？
Doki! Kouiu no ga Koi nano?
ねえ 歌うわ
Hey, I'll sing
そうよ！あなたに
That's right! To you
甘えたいけれど 恥ずかしいかもね
I want to be spoiled, but it might be embarrassing
かもね！ハイ！
Might be! High!
願い事の呪文
A spell for my wish
ホラムニャムニャムニャ
Hora munya munya munya
ハイハイハイハイ！
High high high high!
ずっとこのまま時が
I wish time would stay like this forever
止まらぬかもね
It might not stop
かもね！ハイ！
Might be! High!
こういうのが恋なの
This is what love is
ドキドキドキーン
Doki doki dokiin
ハイハイハイハイ！
High high high high!
しかもね
And also
かもね！ハイ！
Might be! High!
スキススキ
Love love love
ハイハイハイハイ！
High high high high!
昨日よりも...
More than yesterday...
かもね！
Might be!
かもね！ハイ！
Might be! High!
ねえ 歌って
Hey, sing
そうよ！あなたも
That's right! You too
乙女の気持ちが伝わるといいな
I hope a maiden's feelings are conveyed
いいな！ハイ！
Good! High!
喉から出そうなくらい
I'm almost at a loss for words
モブラブラブラブ
Mo love love love love
ハイハイハイハイ！
High high high high!
ずっとこのままあなた
Always like this, you
素敵がいいな
Stay wonderful
いいな！ハイ！
Good! High!
こういうのは初めて
This is the first time
ドキドキドキーン
Doki doki dokiin
ハイハイハイハイ！
High high high high!
あいな
Aina
いいな！ハイ！
Good! High!
スキススキ
Love love love
ハイハイハイハイ！
High high high high!
さっきよりも...
More than before...
いいな！
Good!
いいな！ハイ！
Good! High!
ハイハイハイハイ！
High high high high!
この曲が歌えるなんて…だけ嬉しいです！
I'm just so happy that we could sing this song!
いや、ありがとうございます！
No, thank YOU!
こちらこそいつもいつも踊ってくれてありがとう！
The pleasure is mine, thank you for always dancing with me!
いや、先週はね、団長の２周年ライブに来てくださり…
Well, last week, you came to my 2nd anniversary live...
なんとね、本当ありがとうございます。
...and seriously, thank you so much for that.
今回は、３周年ライブに団長お呼ばれして、すごく嬉しいです！
This time, I'm so happy to be invited to your 3rd anniversary live!
あー、ありがとう！
Ah, thank you!
呼んでこれて嬉しい、ありがとう！
I'm glad I could invite you, thank you!
あやめ先輩、気づいてましたか？
Ayame-senpai, did you notice?
なんですか？
Notice what?
団長たち、二人でこうライブをすると、いつもこういう会話しかしてないです。
Whenever we do a live together, we only ever have this kind of conversation.
そうだね、いつも当たり障りない会話になっちゃってるね。
That's true. It's always very surface-level, isn't it?
団長、あやめ先輩が好きすぎて、あの、目の前に来るとこういう会話しかできなくなる。
I like you too much, Ayame-senpai. When I'm right in front of you, I can only talk like this.
トークスキルがゼロになっちゃうんです。
My talk skills just drop to zero.
まあ、余も元々ないみたいなとこあるから…
Well, I didn't really have much of those to begin with anyway...
あ、そんなことないか。ありがたいけれど…
Ah, maybe that's not true. I'm grateful, but...
ホロメンでトークスキルがあるって言ったら誰を思い浮かべます？
Who in Hololive comes to mind when you think of someone with good talk skills?
そうだね、やっぱマリンちゃんかな？
Let's see... maybe Marine-chan?
やっぱマリンですよね。いやちょっと悔しいけど。
It's definitely Marine, isn't it? It's a bit frustrating, though.
今マリンのいないところだから言えるけど…
I can say this because Marine isn't here, but...
ちょっとマリンのトークは上手だもんね。
Marine's talk skills are quite impressive.
すごいよね、本当に尊敬する。
She's amazing. I really respect her.
羨ましいとこやっぱあるよね。
There's definitely a lot to be envious of.
今欲しいな、マリンのトークスキル。
I wish I had Marine's talk skills right now.
あ、あれ？
Oh? Wait, what?
どーもー！
Hello there!
わ、引かんじゃな！
Whoa, she's not leaving!
あー、腕が折れた！
Ah, my arm broke!
大丈夫か？のいちゃん。
Are you okay, Noi-chan?
まあ、あやめ先輩がこんなにも求めてくれてるから、来ちゃいました。
Well, since Ayame-senpai was asking for me so much, I've arrived.
え？あれ？
Eh? What?
団長まだあやめ先輩と…
I was still with Ayame-senpai...
あれ？お前が帰れよ、お前が帰れよ！
Wait, you should leave! You go home!
よいしょよいしょ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
あー！！
Aaaah!!
なんだこれ、カオスだ。
What is this? This is chaos.
あ、もしかして、二人で歌う感じですか？この後。
Oh, are you two going to sing together after this?
ええー！？
Whaaat!?
いや、お前が呼んだんだ。
Wait, you're the one who called her.
そう、そうなんです、実はね、余がマリンちゃんを呼びました。
Yes, that's right. Actually, I invited Marine-chan.
はい、来させていただきました！
Yes, I have arrived!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
言ってくれればよかったのに！え、じゃあ３人で歌うって感じかな？
You should have told me! Oh, so we're singing as a trio then?
いや、あなたは帰るって感じ。
No, you're going home.
そっか、じゃあちょっと団長名残惜しいけど…
I see. Well, I'm a bit sad to go, but...
あやめ先輩のライブ最高にしたいから、二人で。はい、見てます、あの、センターで。
I want Ayame-senpai's live to be the best, so I'll leave it to you two. I'll be watching from... the center.
邪魔邪魔邪魔。
Move, move, move.
センター、ここで見るわ。本当に３周年おめでとうございました！
I'll watch from right here in the center. Truly, congratulations on your 3rd anniversary!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあねー！気をつけてねー！
Bye-bye! Take care!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あやめ先輩、何か、あれ？こう並んでると何か…
Ayame-senpai, wait. Standing next to each other like this...
…何かお気づきになりませんか？
...don't you notice something?
え、なんですか？
Eh, what is it?
なんだか、なんだか、うちらって…
It's like... it's like we...
…姉妹みたいじゃない！？
...look like sisters, don't we!?
嫌な顔で返事をするな！
Don't give me that look!
すみません、嫌な顔しちゃった。
Sorry, I made a face.
ほら、ミュージック流れてますよ、あやめ先輩。これが、うちら姉妹のＭＭ曲…
Look, the music's starting, Ayame-senpai. This is our sisterly MM song...
…Ｕ＆Ｉ！
...U & I!
キミがいないと何もできないよ
If you're not here, I can't do anything
キミのごはんが食べたいよ
I want to eat your cooking
もしキミが帰ってきたら
If you come back
とびっきりの笑顔で抱きつくよ
I'll hug you with the biggest smile
キミがいないと謝れないよ
If you're not here, I can't apologize
キミの声が聞きたいよ
I want to hear your voice
キミの笑顔が見れれば
If I can see your smile
それだけでいいんだよ
That's all I need
キミがそばにいるだけで
Just having you by my side
いつも勇気もらってた
Always gave me courage
いつまででも一緒にいたい
I want to be together forever
この気持ちを伝えたいよ
I want to convey these feelings
晴れの日も　雨の日も
On sunny days, on rainy days
キミはそばにいてくれた
You were always by my side
目を閉じれば　キミの笑顔
If I close my eyes, your smile...
かがやいてるよ
...is shining
キミがいないと何もわからないよ
If you're not here, I don't understand anything
さとうとしょうゆはどこだっけ？
Where are the sugar and soy sauce?
もしキミが帰ってきたら
If you come back
びっくりさせようと思ったのにな…
I was going to surprise you, but...
キミについつい甘えちゃうよ
I end up depending on you
キミが優しすぎるから
Because you're too kind
キミにもらってばかりで
I'm always receiving from you
なにもあげられてないよ
And haven't given you anything
キミがそばにいることを
The fact that you are by my side...
当たり前に思ってた 君がそばにいることを
I thought it was only natural for you to be by my side.
こんな日々が ずっとずっと 続くんだと思ってたよ
I thought days like these would go on forever and ever.
ごめん 今は気づいたよ 当たり前じゃないことに
Sorry, I've realized now that it's not something to be taken for granted.
まずは君に 伝えなくちゃ ありがとうを…
First, I have to tell you 'Thank you'...
君の胸に 届くかな 今は自信ないけれど
I wonder if it will reach your heart, although I'm not confident right now.
笑わないで どうか聞いて 想いを歌に込めたから
Please don't laugh and listen, because I put my feelings into this song.
ありったけの ありがとうを 歌に乗せて 届けたい
I want to send you all the thanks I can, putting it into a song.
この気持ちは ずっとずっと 忘れないよ
I'll never, ever forget these feelings,
想いよ
These thoughts.
届けー！！
Reach!
なんかちょっとバラバラだったね、ちょっとね
It was a bit out of sync, wasn't it?
ちょっと心がまだ通じ合ってなかったかも...
Our hearts might not have quite connected yet...
あやめ先輩は船長と、これからどんどん心の距離を
Ayame-senpai, with Marine, from now on let's shorten the distance between our hearts...
ちょっと待って
Wait a minute.
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
大丈夫か！歌って踊って、しんどいな
Are you okay?! Singing and dancing is tough.
心の距離を縮めるために、今日呼んでくれたんですもんね
You invited me today to shorten the distance between our hearts, right?
ちょっと無理しないで、大丈夫大丈夫
Don't push yourself, it's okay, it's okay.
でも、これやっぱりします？
But, shall we do this after all?
あ、ちょっと似てるかもね
Ah, we might be a bit similar.
何でちょっと離れるんだ？
Why are you backing away a bit?
でもね！本当に今日は来てくれてありがとうございます！
But really! Thank you so much for coming today!
なんで逃げんの！
Why are you running away!
お前が呼んだんだろ！
You're the one who called me!
逃げるな！
Don't run!
逃げるなー！
Don't run away!
助けてください！すみません！
Help me! I'm sorry!
許さな、逃がさない！
I won't forgive, I won't let you get away!
あー！お嬢！ありがとうございました！
Ah! Ojou! Thank you very much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
どこまでも追いかけるぞ！
I'll chase you to the ends of the earth!
やめてー！
Stop it!
あ！見当たらない、いない
Ah! I can't find it, it's not here.
え、本当にいるの？そんなの
Eh, is it really here? Something like that?
そうや、ここに小さいなきりがいるっていう情報が
Yeah, I have information that there's a tiny Nakiri here.
どれ、どれくらいの確率で出るの？そんなの
So, what's the probability of it appearing?
これ60％だよ、60％
It's 60%, 60%.
え、そんな出るの？
Eh, it appears that much?
いないなー！
It's not here!
あ！なんか通り過ぎた！通り過ぎた！
Ah! Something passed by! It passed by!
あ！もしや...でもこれは大きいなきりだね、小さいなきりじゃない
Ah! Could it be... but this is a big Nakiri, not a tiny one.
え、ってことはこれ、もっとレアなんじゃない？
Eh, does that mean this is even rarer?
あ！レアだ！レアナきりだ！
Ah! It's rare! A rare Nakiri!
レアナきりさん、握手お願いします！
Rare Nakiri-san, please shake hands!
あ、どうも、どうもどうも
Ah, hello, hello hello.
抜けちゃったー！
It came off!
や、すごいなレアだなー
Wow, that's amazing, so rare.
やったなー
We did it.
あ、あの、なんの話ですか？
Um, what are you talking about?
いや、なんか小さいなきりが出るって...
No, just that a tiny Nakiri appears...
そう、ここに小さいなきりが出るんだよ
Yes, a tiny Nakiri appears here.
え、大きいなきり、あ！そう大きいなきりなのかなと思って
Eh, a big Nakiri, ah! I see, a big Nakiri, I thought.
え、なんで走ってきたんですか、今？
Eh, why were you running just now?
あのね、さっきまでマリンちゃんに追いかけ回されてて
Well, I was being chased around by Marine-chan until just now.
怖い！
Scary!
さっきまで歌って踊ってたんですよ
We were singing and dancing until just now.
え、歌って踊ってたの？そんなの
Eh, you were singing and dancing?
え、なんで歌って踊ってたの？
Eh, why were you singing and dancing?
実はね、デビューして、ちょっと3周年なんですよ
Actually, it's my 3rd anniversary since my debut.
おお！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Oh! Congratulations! Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
え、いいの？じゃあ我々もね、3人で踊っていいの？
Eh, is it okay? Then can the three of us dance too?
いいんですか？記念に、いいんですか？
Is it really okay? As a souvenir, is it okay?
ぜひぜひ！お邪魔しましょう
By all means! Let's do it.
え、じゃあ何やる？
Eh, then what shall we do?
そりゃもうあの曲で、あやめがセンターと言えば！
Of course with that song, if Ayame is center!
センターセンター！
Center, center!
の、の、ね、よいしょっとね
And, and, yoishotto-ne.
そう、うちらは、よいしょっとね
Yes, we are, yoishotto-ne.
あ、よいしょっとね、そう
Ah, yoishotto-ne, yes.
行きますよ、せーの！
Here we go, one, two!
百花繚乱花吹雪！
Hyakka Ryouran Hanafubuki!
色づく想いは刹那 百花繚乱花吹雪
Coloring thoughts are but a moment, a profusion of flowers, a blizzard of petals.
パッと咲いて散った　花は終わりにを告げてく
The flowers that bloomed and scattered tell of the end
その時を待てど暮らせど　心は鎮まらず
Though I wait day in and day out for that moment, my heart will not be still
そっと触れて知った　胸の内の温かさを
I learned the warmth within my heart by touching it softly
初めてのこの気持ちだけ　抱きしめていたい
I want to hold onto only this first-time feeling
暁月交わした約束は
The promise we made at dawn
本物だってきっと信じてる
I'm sure it's real, I believe it
いろはにほへとの花に　魅せられた乙女たち
The maidens enchanted by the blooming flowers
ああ　はらりはらりはらり落ちる　花と舞い踊れ
Ah, falling gently, gently, gently, dance along with the flowers
分かち合えた袖も　想い言の葉に込めてみた
I tried putting my feelings into words, even for the sleeves we shared
誰も皆憧れる　現世の理よ
The principles of this world that everyone admires
色付く想いは切な　百花繚乱花吹雪
The colorful feelings are fleeting, a profusion of flowers in a blizzard
ふっと引き消した　夜を灯す月明かりに
In the moonlight that lights up the night I suddenly blew out
曖昧な心が揺れて　声は響かず
My ambiguous heart wavers, and my voice doesn't echo
もっと触れたくて　夢をなぞる指先さえ
Wanting to touch more, even my fingertips tracing dreams
いつの日か果てた形を　忘れかけてた
I had almost forgotten the shape that ended someday
浮世の波にたゆたうと
Swaying in the waves of the floating world
泡沫の夢は弾けてく
The fleeting dreams are bursting
有為の奥山に荒れる　思い達は順序
The feelings running wild in the deep mountains of existence are in order
そろりくらり心揺らめき　歌うは切な歌
Gently and slowly my heart wavers, singing a sad song
浅き夢見しと想い　踏み込むこの世界は
Entering this world with thoughts of shallow dreams
誰も皆憧れる　現世の理よ
The principles of this world that everyone admires
色付く想いは切な　百花繚乱花吹雪
The colorful feelings are fleeting, a profusion of flowers in a blizzard
ひふみ数えて
Count one, two, three
ここにおいで
Come over here
暁月交わした約束は
The promise we made at dawn
本物だってきっと信じてる
I'm sure it's real, I believe it
いろはにほへとの花に　魅せられた乙女たち
The maidens enchanted by the blooming flowers
ああ　はらりはらりはらり落ちる　花と舞い踊れ
Ah, falling gently, gently, gently, dance along with the flowers
分かち合えた袖も　想い言の葉に込めてみた
I tried putting my feelings into words, even for the sleeves we shared
誰も皆憧れる　現世の理よ
The principles of this world that everyone admires
色付く想いは切な　百花繚乱花吹雪
The colorful feelings are fleeting, a profusion of flowers in a blizzard
風に舞う　乙女の純情
Dancing in the wind, a maiden's pure heart
咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly
間違えたー！
I made a mistake!
ちょっと間違えたー！
I made a bit of a mistake!
間違えたー！
I made a mistake!
でも楽しかったよね！
But it was fun, right!
楽しかったね！
It was fun!
みんな歌ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for singing!
こちらこそだよ。おめでとう！
Same here. Congratulations!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！お、じゃあちょっと余も時間なんでね。
Thank you! Oh, well, it's about time for me.
お、ふぇ？急いでちょっと、あ、ステージ戻ります！
Oh, whew? I have to hurry, ah, I'm going back to the stage!
頑張ってねー！バイバーイ！
Good luck! Bye-bye!
あ、小さいなきり見つける？
Ah, did you find the small Nakiri?
確かに。大きいのしか見つかってない。
True. I've only found the big one.
いない、いないよ。
Not there, she's not there.
もうちょっと一回さ、クレープ食べに行かない？
Hey, should we go eat crepes for a bit?
確かに、休憩しようぜ。
True, let's take a break.
甘いもん食べよう。お、じゃあちょっとクレープ食べてきます。
Let's eat something sweet. Oh, well then, we're going to eat some crepes.
クレープ！クレープ！
Crepes! Crepes!
あー！みんな、お待たせしました！
Ah! Everyone, sorry to keep you waiting!
ちょっと急いでね、あのアイドル衣装に着替えて戻ってきましたけれども、
I hurried to change into my idol outfit and came back,
えー、ここら辺でね、ちょっとちょっとお知らせをひとちょっと挟んじゃおうかなー、
And well, right around here, I think I'll squeeze in a little announcement,
おこうかなー、ということでね、ま、何が来るかと言いますと、
I think I will, and so, what's coming is,
みんな行きますよ！重大発表ですよ！いいですか？心の準備はよろしいでしょうか？
Here we go, everyone! It's a major announcement! Are you ready? Is your heart ready?
ということで、百鬼あやめ活動三周年記念グッズ発売します！やったー！
So, Nakiri Ayame 3rd Anniversary commemorative goods are going on sale! Yay!
ということで気になるね、活動三周年記念グッズのフルセットの内容はこちらです。ドドン！
So, here is the contents of the much-anticipated 3rd Anniversary commemorative goods full set. Ta-da!
抱き枕カバーとボイスのセットになっております。
It's a set with a body pillow cover and voice recordings.
活動三周年記念フルセット
Activity 3rd Anniversary Full Set
ヤッター！ちょっと、みんな、
Yay! Wait, everyone,
みんな待ってたんじゃないのー？ちょっとね、みんな、
Haven't you all been waiting? You know, everyone,
他のメンバーとかもね、出している中、
while other members have been releasing theirs,
あれ？余の抱き枕カバーって
wait, where's my hug pillow cover?
まだなんですか？
isn't it out yet?
え？まだ出ないんですか？なんてね、
Eh? It's not out yet? Or something like that,
お声も、まあ、あったりなかったりみたいな、
there were voices, well, maybe some or not many,
あったんですけど、えー、ということで今回、
there were some, and so, this time,
待ちに待った抱き枕カバー発売させていただきますよー！
the long-awaited hug pillow cover is finally being released!
え、表面がですね、余がいつも着ている和服と
Well, the front side is the kimono I always wear,
イラスト：ななかぐら先生
Illustration: Nana Kagura-sensei
裏面が、夏仕様の水着となっております！
and the back side is a summer-style swimsuit!
フルセットにはね、なんと、なんと！
And for the full set, believe it or not,
数量限定で直筆のサイン入りのポストカードついてきます！
it comes with a limited-edition hand-signed postcard!
余がね、頑張って一生懸命書きますよ！
I'll work hard and write them with all my heart!
直筆サイン入りポストカード
Hand-signed Postcard
でね、ちょっと数量に限りがあるので、
And since they're in limited quantities,
数量を超えた場合は、えーと、箔押しのきんぴかの余のサインがついてくることになります。
if the limit is exceeded, they'll come with a shiny gold foil-stamped signature.
で、気になるシチュエーションボイスはですね、
And as for the situation voice you're curious about,
三周年記念海デート、というボイスになっておりますので、
it's called "3rd Anniversary Ocean Date," so
ぜひ皆さん、ちょっとね、恥ずかしいですけど、聞いてくれたら嬉しいななんて思います！
I'd be happy if everyone would listen to it, even though it's a bit embarrassing!
で、これはね、書いてくださったのは、余の母上、ななかぐら、
And the one who drew this is my mother-artist, Nana Kagura,
シチュエーションボイス「三周年記念海デート」
Situation Voice: "3rd Anniversary Ocean Date"
ななかぐら先生となっております！母上ありがとう！
it's Nana Kagura-sensei! Thank you, Mother!
ぜひぜひね、すいません、あの、疲れてきましたね、
Please do, sorry, um, I'm getting a bit tired,
ぜひぜひ皆さんお買い求めくださいませーということで、
so please do buy it, everyone. And so,
まあ、あの、お知らせも一通りしましたし、
well, I've finished with the announcements,
10月3日(日) 販売開始
Sales start on October 3rd (Sun)
まあまままあ、あの、三周年の配信は
well, the 3rd-anniversary stream
まあここらへんでもいいかなー
might be good to end here...
なんてことは、ないですよ！
Just kidding, that's not it!
皆さん、あと一つお知らせがありますからね！
Everyone, I have one more announcement!
なんと、みんな、もうこれこそ待ちに待ったんじゃないかという
Believe it or not, this is surely what you've all been waiting for,
ことがありますね！ありますね！
right? Right?
そうです。余がまだ出してないものが、まだ一つありますね！
That's right. There's still one thing I haven't released yet!
そう！余のオリジナルソングをここで発表したいと思います！
Yes! I'd like to announce my original song here!
ヤッター！ドンドンパフパフー！ということで、
Yay! *celebratory sounds* So,
皆を待ちに待たせた余の一曲目のね、記念すべきオリジナルソングが
the memorable first original song that kept you all waiting
ここでお披露目されますので、
will be unveiled here, so
みんなね、ちょっと合いの手とかも覚えていってくれたら嬉しいななんて思います！
I'd be happy if everyone could learn the call-and-response and join in!
もう余を表した曲なんで、ぜひ聞いていってください。
It's a song that represents me, so please give it a listen.
じゃあ、いきますよ！余オリジナルソングで
Okay, here we go! With my original song,
「宵の余、良い！」
"Yoi no Yo, Yoi!"
ヤー！
Ya!
宵の余、良い？
Yoi no Yo, Yoi?
パンパンパンパン！
Clap clap clap clap!
百鬼夜行　音頭上々　今夜は眠れない
The Hyakki Yagyo march is in full swing, no sleep tonight
連日連夜　遊び尽くそう　難事必至だっだっだっだだ
Playing all day and night, difficulties are inevitable-da-da-da-da-da
千万無量　溢れてくる　くすぐる好奇心
Infinite feelings overflow, tickling curiosity
優柔反対　これで決めよう　じゃんけんぽいよ　あいこでしょ
Indecisiveness, let's settle it with this: rock-paper-scissors, draw!
パッとパッと開いた
Bursting open wide
ヨイヨイヨイヨイ
Yoi yoi yoi yoi
ワッとワッと言わせる　花火を打ち上げよう
Let's set off fireworks that'll make everyone go "Wow!"
歌え踊れ　右に回れ　一陽来復　暁の宴
Sing and dance, turn to the right, winter turns to spring, the dawn banquet
さあ騒げ　夜に集え　可憐な鬼は内
Come on, make some noise, gather in the night, the lovely oni is in
歌え踊れ　前に倣え　凡庸それすらも愛嬌
Sing and dance, follow the leader, even mediocrity is charming
さあ騒げ　暁まで　可憐な鬼は内
Come on, make some noise until dawn, the lovely oni is in
退屈舞い踊る　大喝采をさらう　音に乗せられて
Boredom dances away, stealing a grand applause, carried by the sound
なんてったって精々　派手に舞って　天真爛漫　ヨイノヨヨイ
After all, just dance brilliantly, innocent and cheerful, Yoi no Yo, Yoi!
パンパンパンパン！
Clap clap clap clap!
明鏡止水　目を瞑って　ひと休み寝ちゃって
Serene mind, closing eyes, taking a little nap
美味佳肴　味わったら　感激必至だっだっだっだだ
Once you taste the delicacies, deep emotion is inevitable-da-da-da-da-da
永永無窮　終わりたくない　何して遊ぼうか
Forever and ever, I don't want it to end, what should we play?
暗中模索　これで決めよう　じゃんけんぽいよ　あいこでしょ
Groping in the dark, let's settle it with this: rock-paper-scissors, draw!
グッとグッと堪えて
Holding it in tight
ヨイヨイヨイヨイ
Yoi yoi yoi yoi
ワッとワッと沸くほど　太鼓を打ち鳴らそう
Let's beat the drums until everyone's cheering with excitement
泣いて笑え　世に続け　きらきらのきんぴか掲げ
Cry and laugh, continue through the world, raising the sparkling gold
さあおいで　拒まないで　可憐な鬼は内
Come on over, don't refuse, the lovely oni is in
泣いて 笑って 前に進め
Cry, laugh, and move forward
期待外れ でも 良いぞ
Even if it's disappointing, it's fine
さあ おいで 遠慮無用
Come on over, no need to hold back
華麗な 鬼は内
The magnificent ogre is inside
抱腹絶倒 想像 夜を飾る
Hilariously imaginative, decorating the night
眩しい 声に 釣られて
Lured by that dazzling voice
なんだかんだ 最高
One way or another, it's the best
派手に舞った
Dancing flashy
天真爛漫 宵 宵 宵
Innocent and cheerful, Yo, Yo, Yo
よだぞ！ こっからはもっともっと盛り上げるために、
It's me! To heat things up even more from here,
みんなにあいのてを打ってもらおうと思うよ。
I'd like everyone to join in with the call and response.
余に続いてちゃんとついてきてね。
Follow my lead and keep up, okay?
行くよ。せーの！
Here we go. One, two!
ヨイ ヨイ ヨヨイノ ヨイ ヨイ ヨヨイ
Yoi, yoi, yo-yoi-no, yoi, yoi, yo-yoi
せっせっせーの ヨイ ヨイ ヨイ
Ready, set, go! Yoi, yoi, yoi
振り乱す
Wildly dancing
せっせっせーの ヨイ ヨイ ヨイで
Ready, set, go! With a Yoi, yoi, yoi
浮世を埋め尽くせ
Fill up this fleeting world
歌え 踊れ 右に回れ
Sing, dance, and turn to the right
いきよいぴか一だ 歌え
Your spirit is number one, sing!
さあ 騒げ 夜 集え
Come on, make some noise, gather in the night
華麗な 鬼は内
The magnificent ogre is inside
歌え 踊れ 前にならえ
Sing, dance, and follow the leader
ポンコツ それすらも愛嬌
Being a klutz? Even that's charming!
さあ 騒げ 夜更かしまで
Come on, make some noise until late at night
華麗な 鬼は内
The magnificent ogre is inside
正真正銘 此処が 喝采を 攫う
Truly, this is the place that steals the applause
音に 乗せられて
Carried away by the sound
なんてったって 盛大
Because, after all, it's magnificent
派手に舞った
Dancing flashy
天真爛漫 宵 宵 宵
Innocent and cheerful, Yo, Yo, Yo
THANKS FOR WATCHING ご視聴ありがとうございます
THANKS FOR WATCHING Thank you for watching